Tim Huitt

Broomfield, CO 80021 | 914-960-1960

timhuitt@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/timhuitt/ | github.com/timhuitt | timhuitt.com

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

I'm an experienced Software Engineer with a passion for innovative problem-solving. Self-taught and formally educated, I excel in leadership, team guidance, and process optimization. My track record includes leadership roles and the development of Python and VBA full-stack applications.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Node.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap **Databases and other:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: Leadership, Team Guidance, Training, Project Coordination, Client Communication, Relationship Building, Management, Process Optimization, Communication Skills, Problem-Solving, Self-Motivation, Adaptability

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Battleship - GitHub | App - Javascript, HTML, CSS

Submarine-themed Battleship Game, with a smart computer opponent.

- ❖ Built custom classes to handle grid creation and pop-up alerts
- Developed an advanced computer player that chooses cells based on previous hits
- Created a custom interface with a traditional Battleship/submarine theme

SD Manager - Overview - Python, TKInter

Software tool for video analysis and data transfer management

- ❖ Implemented custom UI to enable video filtering by time and date ranges
- Created a video review, displaying selected segments, extracted data from video and allowing mousewheel scrubbing
- ❖ Handled transfer of sequential video files, automatically naming, routing, and organizing files

App Name - GitHub | App - Coding language used | Coding language used

One sentence about what the app does, think of this like a one-line marketing pitch

- Bullet points that describe the features you created in your app. Use the formula:
- ❖ Action verb + what you did + result
- ❖ Action verb + what you did + result

EXPERIENCE

Denver Data Analytics - Project Manager / Software Developer

Denver, CO, 02/2021 - 08/2023

- Designed, developed and deployed multiple full-stack applications, providing greater data/processing efficiency
- ❖ Worked with and managed a small group to collect and compile analytical data for private/municipal clients
- ❖ Deployed, operated, maintained, and oversaw the use of advanced data collection equipment

Lightshade - Manager

Federal Heights, CO, 03/2019 - 01/2021

- ❖ Built multiple Excel applications to reduce time spent on redundant tasks
- ♦ Managed a retail establishment with 30+ employees and up to \$100,000/day in sales
- ❖ Directed and oversaw the operations, including cash/employee management, inventory/ordering, scheduling

Merrill Lynch - Senior Financial Advisor

Ridgefield, CT, 08/2012 - 02/2018

- Created Excel applications to assist with managing client information, bookkeeping, and record keeping
- ❖ Assisted 30+ affluent clients with asset and liability management
- Worked on a team of 4 advisors with over 200 clients and \$500,000,000 in managed funds
- Managed investment portfolios, retirement/education accounts, insurance, mortgages,

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote, Certificate Expected: 01/2024

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Fullsail University, Bachelor of Arts

Winter Park, FL 12/2011